Preliminary Guide to the Jerry D. Campbell records, 1930-1998 (bulk 1989-1994)
Duke University. University Archives
Jerry D. Campbell records 1930-1998 (bulk 1989-1994)
Duke University. Library
25 linear feet Extent: 35,000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
Contains records of the Duke University Library Administration, primarily under Jerry D. Campbell's administration, ca. 1984-1995. Types of materials include subject files, correspondence, minutes, annual reports, budgets, evaluations, contracts, and miscellaneous notes pertaining to the operation and management of the Duke University Libraries since around 1930. Major topics include academic library administration, space utilization, statistics, Jerry D. Campbell, information networks, library cooperation, catalog automation, and budgets. The bulk of materials (A2002-88) are from 1989-1994. English.
UA.08.01.0008
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice required for use.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
Transfer; 2002; A2002-88.
Historical Note
The libraries of Duke University consist of the William R. Perkins Library and its seven branches on campus: Biological and Environmental Sciences, Chemistry, Lilly, Engineering, Music, Mathematics-Physics, Special Collections; the Pearse Memorial Library at the Duke Marine Laboratory in Beaufort; and the independently administered libraries of Divinity, Law, Medicine, and Business (Ford Library). As of June 1996, these libraries contained over 4,534,000 volumes. The collection includes eleven million manuscripts, and over two million public documents. The Libraries are directed by the Vice Provost for Library Affairs.
Collection Overview
Contains subject files, correspondence, minutes, annual reports, budgets, evaluations, contracts, and miscellaneous notes pertaining to the operation and management of the Duke University Libraries from about 1930-1994. The bulk of materials were created by Jerry D. Campbell's administration, circa 1984-1995.
Subject Headings
Academic libraries -- Administration; Academic libraries -- space utilization; Academic libraries -- statistics; Academic libraries -- North Carolina -- Durham; Campbell, Jerry Dean; Duke University. Library; Library administration; Library catalogs -- automation; Library cooperation; Library buildings -- North Carolina --Durham; Library information networks -- North Carolina; Library materials budgets
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- A2002-88
  - Administration files, A-E, 1983-1985 (bulk 1990-1991) (Box 1)
  - Librarian's publication files (Box 1)
  - Administration files, F-Z, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
    Includes compact shelving, five-year plan, some annual reports
  - University Librarian, A-Z subject files, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - University Librarian, A-Z subject files, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SOLINET, 1978-1988 (Box 5)
  - Jerry D. Campbell committees, A-M, ca. 1989-1993 (Box 6)
    Includes Dean's Council, Arts and Sciences Council
  - Jerry D. Campbell committees, N-S, ca. 1989-1993 (Box 7)
    Includes Science Resource Initiative, Provost's Staff
  - Jerry D. Campbell committees, T-U, ca. 1989-1993 (Box 8)
    Includes TelCom, Dr. William C. Young/U.S. Department of Education, some TRLN ca. 1990
  - TRLN ca. 1991 (Box 9)
  - Library Departments, A-Ca, ca. 1983-1989 (Box 9)
    Includes Lubans correspondence, 1988-1989
  - Library Departments Ca-M (and Systems), ca. 1988-1992 (Box 10)
  - Library Departments, N-S, ca. 1985-1993 (bulk 1989-1990) (Box 11)
    Includes Fuqua, Law and Medical Libraries, ca. 1989-1994
  - Library Committees, A-B, 1987-1991 (Box 11)
  - Library Committees, D-S, 1987-1991 (Box 12)
    Includes Librarian's Assembly, Library Development, Recognition Committee
  - Preservation Committee (Box 13)
  - FLIP/PLOTS staff development (Box 13)
  - Executive Group (Box 13)
    Includes Supervisor's Forum, Support Staff Council, Funding Model Committee, Task Force on Machine-Readable Data Files
  - North Carolina Information Highway, ca. 1985-1994 (Box 13)
  - Library statistics, growth and holdings and miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - NCHED/HEGIS, 1968-1987 (Box 14)
  - IPEPS, 1988-1992 (Box 14)
  - Library use surveys, ca. 1980-1988 (Box 14)
  - Statistics for Technical Services (Box 15)
  - Southern Colleges and University Libraries, ca. 1985-1991 (Box 15)
  - General files A-E, ca. 1988-1992 (Box 15)
    Includes building plans, Center for the Book, compact shelving, Dead Sea Scrolls, Divinity School renovation, Duke Press, Duke Hotel, and Educom
  - General files F-R, ca. 1988-1992 (Box 16)
    Includes four-millionth volume, fire alarms, Gothic Bookstore, INNOVACQ/Innopac, Master of Library Science program proposals, organizational charts, outstanding service awards, Peat-Marwich-Mitchell contractor analysis, space inventory, remote storage
  - General files S-U, ca. 1988-1993 (Box 17)
    Includes space problems, Tandem, University Presses.
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies (Box 17)
  - Short writings and reprints (Box 17)
  - Staff development, ca. 1990-1991 (Box 17)
  - SOLINET, 1989-1994 (Box 18)
  - Library Council, 1981-1986, 1989-1991 (Box 18)
  - Interim University Librarian, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Interim University Librarian, 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - Library accreditation records, 1997-1998 (Box 21)
Related Material
Friends of Duke University Library records.
University Archives, Duke University.